ncleg.net 2006-12-28

# North Carolina General Assembly - Privacy Statement

| Site Navigation  
---  
 | Home|    
 | House|    
 | Senate|    
 | Committees|    
 | Legislation/Bills|    
 | Representation|    
 | Legislative Library|    
 | NCGA Information|    
 | Audio|    
 | Citizen Guide|    
 | Help|    
Quick Links  
  
NCGA Job Vacancies

  * NC Statutes
  * Redistricting
  * NC Constitution
  * NC Session Laws
  * Legislative Publications
  * NCGA Stormwater Water Collection Project
  * State Government Site
  * Lobbyist Info
  * Other Government Sites

Site Information  
 | Disclaimer|    
 | Privacy Statement|    
 | Policies|    
 | Contact Us|    
  
Privacy Statement

**Use of Information:

THE NORTH CAROLINA GENERAL ASSEMBLY DOES NOT SELL, RENT, LOAN, TRADE, LEASE OR OTHERWISE TRANSFER ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED ON OUR SITE, INCLUDING E-MAIL LISTS, TO ANY THIRD PARTY. WE WILL TREAT ANY INFORMATION YOU PROVIDE AS CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION AND WILL NOT DISCLOSE IT TO ANY THIRD PARTY.

Summary of Information Collected and Stored Automatically 

**

When you visit our website to browse, read pages, or download information, we automatically collect and store **only** the following information:  
1\. The Internet domain and IP address from which you access our portal;   
2\. The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;   
3\. The date and time you access our site;   
4\. The pages you visit; and   
5\. If you linked to the NCGA site from another Web site, the address of that Web site. 

The NCGA uses this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors, and to learn about the number of visitors to our site.

**Web Site Security:**  
For Web site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, the state utilizes a computer system that employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. These attempts to cause damage or unauthorized access to confidential data could be subject to legal action according to N.C.G.S. § 14-453 - 459.

**Links to Other Web Sites:**  
The North Carolina General Assembly Web site contains links to other Web sites. The North Carolina General Assembly is not responsible for the privacy practices or the of such Web sites.

**Cookies:**  
A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your Web browser (your computer's hard drive) so it can later be read back from that browser. A cookie file can contain certain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you have visited on that site. If you are interested, more information on cookies can be found by visiting the Cookie Central web site at [http://www.cookiecentral.com/](http://www2.ncleg.net/gascripts/redirects/ExitDisclaimer.pl?http://www.cookiecentral.com/)

The NCGA website uses cookies in its Bill Inquiry system if you choose to log in with your ID and password. Doing this stores your information on your computer allowing you to skip the login process for each future visit to the Load/Save section of Bill Inquiry. You can Sign Out after logging in, which will remove your ID and password from your computer, causing the Login screen to appear before future Load/Save attempts. 

**Privacy of Our E-Mail Lists:**  
The NCGA maintains e-mail lists, but only of those individuals or organizations that have specifically opted to receive updates and other information from the NCGA. These lists include members of the media and interested members of the general public who have specifically requested to be kept informed about the House and Senate calendars.

**Individuals must affirmatively request to be placed on our lists. Any personal information provided by such individuals will be used only to send the users such information.**

We do not sell, rent, loan, trade, or lease the addresses on our lists to anyone. In addition, we configure our list server software to refuse to divulge the e-mail addresses of our list subscribers to anyone including other list subscribers.  
Individuals wishing to unsubscribe their email address may do so at the following page: Subscribe/Unsubscribe from the House & Senate Distribution List

If you send us e-mail with a question or comment, we will use your e-mail address only to respond to you. We will store your e-mail, e-mail address, and a copy of our response for archival purposes only. We will archive such information only for the length of time necessary to fulfill these archival purposes. At the conclusion of such time, we will delete such archived information.

**Length of Time Data Will Be Stored:**  
Unless you request that we delete any of the information you submitted when you registered for any electronic updates and/or newsletters we may offer, we will store such information indefinitely. 

|  | Calendars  
---  
House| [[archive]](https://web.archive.org/gascripts/DocumentSites/browseDocSite.asp?nID=2&sFolderName=/House)  
Senate| [[archive]](https://web.archive.org/gascripts/DocumentSites/browseDocSite.asp?nID=2&sFolderName=/Senate)  
Legislative| [[archive]](https://web.archive.org/LegislativeCalendar/LegislativeCalendar.pl?view=TOC)  
Site Searches  
Bill Look-Up  
  
 Example: S456   
S.L. Look-Up  
  
 Example: 46   
Statute Look-Up  
  
 Example: 17D-4   
Bill Text
